中文字幕来源：bilibili
英文字幕来源：iPlayer
OCR/双语合并/调轴：James丶xz
9号秘事
第七季   第五集
随手行善
Tinder是一款手机社交应用程式，常用于约会与一夜情
鲍勃·布利斯
与晚期疾病共存
节哀顺变
致以最深切的慰问
量子跨越者
扎卡里·威尔逊和鲁道夫·布兰 我们时代的时间旅行者
牛顿第一定律指出
Newton's first law states that an object in motion...
任何运动的物体都将保持运动状态
..will remain in motion unless an external force...
直到外力迫使它改变
..imposes a change upon it.
任何处于静止状态的物体 同样将保持静止
Similarly, an object at rest will remain at rest
直到有一个不平衡的力施加影响
until an unbalanced force affects it.
它也被称为惯性定律
This is also known as the law of inertia.
你好 今天过得怎样
Hi, how was your day?
有什么吃的吗
Is there any food?
有 你面前的冰箱里都是食物
Yes, there's a whole fridge full of food in front of you.
都是橄榄和鹰嘴豆泥之类的垃圾
Yeah, but it's all olives and hummus and shit.
有什么真正能吃的东西吗
Something to actually eat?
不是每顿饭都能直接用托盘端到面前
Um, not every meal comes in a tray, Zach.
有些要用我们所谓的“食材”烹饪
Some are made with what we humans call ingredients.
不要把所有的麦片都吃光
Don't eat all the cereal, please.
不然明天早上就没了
There'll be none left for the morning.
你能把它关掉的 懂吗
You can turn that off, you know.
关掉什么
Turn what off?
这个愚蠢的声音
That stupid sound.
我喜欢
I like it.
谁叫我没有一个自带敲击声的键盘呢
It makes up for not having a proper bloomin' keyboard.
你到底在做什么
What are you actually doing?
如果你一定要问的话 我在预约子宫涂片检查
I'm booking a smear test, if you must know.
是你要问的
Well, you asked.
我都听得头疼了
It's giving me a migraine.
别夸张了
Don't exaggerate.
我想让你静音
Just disable clicks!
我不想静音 要静音你静音
I don't want to disable clicks! You disable clicks.
我之前静音了
I have done.
那就得了
Fine, then.
你今天过得怎么样
So, how was your day?
成绩下来了吗
Did you get your results back?
扎卡里
Zachary?
下来了
Yes.
我得了个B
I got a B.
你到底想怎样
What do you actually want?
我想和你谈一谈
It'd be nice if we could just talk.
想说什么就说吧 我又没有拦着你
You can talk, I'm not stopping you.
我是说谈话
I mean...a conversation,
彼此沟通一下
a bit of back and forth,
我一个人在这里待了一整天了
I've been here on my own all day.
这不是我的错
That's not my fault.
这样的要求不过分吧
I don't think it's too much to ask to just sit
我们抽个晚上坐在一起 聊上半个小时
and have half an hour together of an evening.
听着 我又不是你的男朋友
Look, I'm not your boyfriend.
如果你想和别人说话 就去用约会软件
If you want to talk to someone, go on...Tinder.
我来到这个世界上不是为了满足你
I wasn't put on this Earth to make you happy.
你再说一遍
You can say that again.
-你什么意思 -没什么意思
-What's that supposed to mean?  -Nothing.
你想跟抛弃爸爸那样抛弃我吗
You want to bin me off like you did Dad?
当然不是
Of course I don't.
而且是他自己离开的 不是我逼的
And it was him who walked out, remember? Not me.
这怪不得他
I don't blame him.
如果我能回到过去 做出一些改变
Look, if I could go back and do things differently,
我非常乐意 但是扎克
I would do, but, Zach,
回不去了 拜托
can't we, please, live together
我们能不能好好过日子 不要一直吵
without all of this constant argy-bargy?
让我们都少些抱怨吧
Let's cut the beef, bro.
现在大家都不这么说了
No-one says beef any more.
真可恶
Oh, bloody hell...
是这样
Ah, yes, I, er...
我发现了这只小鸟 双写T
I found this little - double T - bird
-就在你的房子外面 -怎么
-Just outside your house. -Right.
很不巧 由于玻璃反光 它直接撞了上去
They fly towards their reflections in the windows, unfortunately.
天哪
Oh, dear.
你觉得我们能为它做些什么吗
Can we do anything for it, do you think?
你有没有一个小箱子 双写L
Er, if you had a small - double L - box
把它安置在一处安静的地方
and a quiet space, he might just come to.
我有 请进吧
Um, yes. Yeah, come in.
谢谢你
Oh, thank you.
希望它没有脑震荡
Hopefully, it's not a concussion.
像是一只麻雀 双写R
Sparrow, I think - double R.
坚强的老鸟
Aw... They're tough old birds.
可怜的家伙
Poor thing.
我可以放它吧
Er, shall I, er...?
可以 对了 我叫海伦
Oh, yeah. I'm Helen, by the way.
我叫鲍勃
Oh, erm, Bob.
鲍勃·布利斯 双写S
Bob Bliss - double S.
至少我们知道它的内脏还在工作
At least we know his insides are functioning.
你怎么知道的
How?
哦 这里有水
Oh, here. Ooh!
谢谢你
Thank you, thanks.
你真是个好人
It's very kind of you.
很多人都无动于衷的
A lot of people wouldn't have cared.
我要抚养一个十几岁的孩子
Oh, well, I have a teenager, so...
再照顾一个小生命算得了什么
..what's another feeble creature to look after?
我的两个孩子现在都已经飞走了
Both of mine have flown the nest now.
你很幸运
Oh, lucky you.
不 我不应该这么说
No, I shouldn't say that.
-他是个小数学家吗 -谁
-So, is he the mathematician? -He?
你的孩子 双写E
Er, your teenager - double E.
扎克 没错 他在学习高中课程
Oh, Zach, yes, yes. He's doing his A levels.
选了数学 物理和化学 老天保佑
Yeah, maths, physics and chemistry, God help him.
选得好
Ha, great combo.
我曾在剑桥大学攻读物理学博士
I did my PhD in physics at Cambridge
那是许多年前的事了
a few years ago.
物理这门课太有趣了 但想学好物理
It's a fascinating subject, but a lot of it does depend
老师非常重要
on the teaching.
不好意思
Excuse me.
说得对 扎克的老师很糟糕 他和我说过
Yes. Zach's teachers are terrible, so he tells me.
这都是 双写L 相较而言的
It's all - double L - relative, so, er...
这是我的儿子 扎克
Aw, this is my son, Zach.
很高兴见到你 双写E
Pleased to - double E - meet you.
可恶
Oh, bloody hell!
拜托
Come on. Oh!
它飞走了
There he goes!
扎克 这是鲍勃
Zach, this is Bob.
鲍勃以前在剑桥学习物理
Bob studied physics at Cambridge.
你不打个招呼吗
Aren't you even going to say hi?
你好
Hi.
不祥的预兆
Jinx!
噢 你是让他跟我打招呼 对不起
Oh, you meant him say hi to me? Apologies, er...
扎克 你现在可以说话了
Zach, you can speak now.
我知道我可以 我又不是八岁小孩
I know I can. I'm not eight years old.
就像一个铀238
Right, as one uranium-238 nucleus
对另一个铀238说的那样
said to the other uranium-238 nucleus,
我要裂了
"I've got to split."
他懂了
He gets it.
很高兴见到你 海伦
Yeah, it's nice to have met you, Helen.
扎克 祝你学习顺利
Er, Zach, best of luck with your studies.
希望老师的教学能有所提高
Hope that teaching improves.
如果你遇到了困难 我就住在附近
I live close by, if you ever wanted to go through anything.
等等 不好意思
Wait, erm...sorry.
你平时愿不愿意做家教呢
You don't do any tutoring, do you?
扎克必须提高他的成绩
It's just that Zach needs to punch up his predicted grades.
-妈妈 -现实就是这样
-Mum! -Well, it's true!
你不想像鲍勃那样考进一所好大学吗
Don't you want to get into a good uni, like Bob did?
你真是太过分了 我好尴尬
She's so cringy, it's embarrassing.
我现在确实有一些空闲时间
I do have some spare time at the moment.
换句话说我还没有成天忙碌 双写L
That is to say, I'm not fully - double L - engaged, erm...
我可以在周四的6点过来
Yeah, why don't I come round Thursday at six,
看看 双写E 我们进展如何
see - double E - how we get on?
-能不能帮上扎克的忙 -很好 无论如何
-And then if Zach thinks it's useful... -Yeah, whatever.
我只要不和她在一起就行
Anything to avoid spending time with her.
牛顿第二运动定律 其最简单的形式
Newton's second law of motion, in its simplest form,
可以用方程式F=MA表示
can be expressed by the equation F=ma,
或者说力等于质量乘以加速度
or force equals mass times acceleration.
这就是为什么施加相同的力时
It's why this car, which has a greater mass,
质量较大的这辆车
will travel less far than this car
没有质量较小的走得远
when identical force is applied.
真是太棒了 扎克
Oh, this is top-notch, Zach.
做得好 双写L
Well - double L - done.
记得在上面写上日期
Remember to put the, er, date on the top.
62年 那是你出生的时候吗
'62? Is that when you were born?
是啊 恐怕我已经很老了
Yes, yes, I'm afraid I am rather old.
为什么F=MA是第二定律的一个特例呢
So why is F=ma a special case of the second law?
它假定质量保持不变
Well, it assumes that the mass remains constant.
使用了一个惯性参照系
It uses an inertial frame of reference.
这意味着什么
Which means?
就是说没有外力作用于它
That there are no outside forces acting on it
使它加速
that make it accelerate.
很好 双写O
Very good - double O.
那么现在有什么外力作用在你身上呢
So, what outside forces are acting on you right now?
重力
Gravity,
地球旋转
the Earth spinning,
还有你
you...
你被推得越猛 就能走得越远 对吧
And the harder you're pushed, the further you can travel, yes?
好了 谢谢
OK. Thanks.
我不小心瞥见了你的文身
I, erm... I couldn't help but notice your tattoo
双写T 双写O
Double T - double O -
是啊
Yeah, er...
我这么做只是为了让我妈生气
I only did it to piss my mum off.
有用吗
And did it work?
她没有注意到
She hasn't noticed.
这就是她对我的关心程度
That's how much she cares about me.
我觉得她是关心你的 扎克
Oh, I think she does care, Zach.
我想她非常关心你 双写E
I think she cares very deeply - double E -
但是你知道受力相同的物体
but, as you know, objects with the same force
互相排斥
Do repel each other.
是的
Yeah.
不是我故意打听 你父亲是
I don't want to pry, but, erm, is your father...?
他住在新加坡
Oh. He, er, lives in Singapore.
现在有了新的家庭
He's got a new family now, so...
我很少能见到他
..I don't really get to see him that often.
对你和你母亲来说
That must be hard.
一定很困难
For you and for your mother.
我无所谓
I don't have a problem with it.
她才是那个该死的疯子
She's the one that's fuckin' mental.
-这个词说得太重了 -你又没有和她一起生活
-That's a strong word to use. -You don't have to live with her.
扎克
Zach...
-其实我 -晚餐好了
-I'm... -Dinner's ready!
好吧
OK.
-真好 谢谢你 -你确定不想喝一杯吗
-That was lovely, thank you. -Sure you don't want a glass?
不 这样挺好
No, no, I'm fine.
就一杯吗
Just one?
-说真的 -就一点儿
-Honestly. -Just a little bit?
-说真的 可以了 -好吧 我再来一点
-Honestly, I'm fine. -OK. Well, more for me.
我有一项家庭作业给你
Hey, I've got some homework for you.
周六就是国家障碍赛马大赛
It's the Grand National on Saturday.
你现在研究一下马匹和骑师的重量
Now, study the weights of the horses and the jockeys.
用物理学来预测一下赢家 双写N
Try and use physics to pick us out a winner - double N.
你这是在教他赌博
You're teaching him gambling?
有些不负责任
That's not very responsible.
如果你提前知道赢家 就不算赌博
It's not gambling if you know who's going to win.
为我选一匹马 扎克
Pick me one, Zach.
你自己选吧
Pick your own!
如果你不介意我问的话
So... What do you do with your days?
你平时都做些什么
If you don't mind me asking.
不介意
No, erm...
我兼职做簿记员 双写O 双写K 双写E
I work part time as a book-keeper - double O, double K, double E.
有点拗口
A bit of a mouthful.
确实
Yes.
要是你以打蛋谋生的话
Well...you could be... ..an egg batterer,
你每天就会说
and then you'd say,
双写G和双写T
"Double G and T," every day!
最后就会很恼火
You'd end up pissed!
那么继续说
So, go on,
你为什么要这样做 鲍勃
why do you do it, Blob...Bob?
鲍勃·布利斯
Bob Bliss.
你能不能别审问他了
Stop interrogating him.
这叫谈话 扎克
What? It's called conversation, Zach.
倾听和学习
Listen and learn.
继续说 双写X双写L都是怎么回事
Go on, what's it all about? Double X, double L?
我想 双写P 这是一种轻微的强迫症
Well, I suppose - double P - it's, er, a mild form of OCD.
作为一个物理学学生
As a student of physics,
我一直在努力寻找模式 双写T
I was constantly trying to find patterns - double T -
先是在数据和数字中找
in data and numbers,
然后又在文字中找
and then in words.
这么做令我感到平静
Yeah, I find it calming.
我明白了 有时你感觉一切都要分崩离析
I get it. When everything feels like it's unravelling,
就想努力抓住一些东西 就像我点击键盘时发出的音效
and you've just got to hold on to something. It's like my clicks.
我需要这个声音 他想关掉这个声音
I need my clicks, and he doesn't want me to have them,
但我不愿意 它是为我准备的
but I say, "No, they're for me."
烦人
Fuck's sake.
扎克 回来 现在回来
Zach, come back. Come back now.
凭什么
Why?
这样我就可以坐在那里 听你聊一晚上废话吗
So I can sit there and listen to you chat shit all night?
你太可悲了
You're pathetic.
别想太多
It's OK, honestly.
这只是他的荷尔蒙作祟
I dare say, it's just his hormones,
加上他爸爸离家的原因
plus his dad walking out.
正好碰上我的荷尔蒙 加上红酒 雪上加霜
Up against my hormones, plus red wine - not a good combo.
我敢说我们在他这个年纪 双写L 也是一样的
I'm sure we were all - double L - the same at his age.
或许我可以花更多时间和他在一起
Maybe if I could spend more time with him, I...
为什么大自然会这样安排
Why does nature do it, eh?
在我们的孩子变成野蛮的怪物时
Give us the menopause
正好赶上我们绝经
just as our kids are becoming feral monsters.
科学能解释这个吗
Can science explain that?
他不是怪物
He's not a monster.
绝对不是
He's not.
他只是正值叛逆期罢了
He's just...an angry young man.
我太累了 鲍勃
I'm so tired, Bob.
我知道
I know.
好了 我要走了
Right, I'd best be off.
谢谢你的晚餐
Thanks for dinner
双写N
double N.
还有双写F 走了
And double F - off.
双写F 走了
Double F - off.
力是指一个物体
A force is a push or a pull
与另一个物体相互作用
that acts upon an object
而作用于该物体的推力或拉力
as a result of its interaction with another object.
这些力遵从牛顿第三运动定律
These forces are subject to Newton's third law of motion.
作用力和反作用力大小相等方向相反
For every action, there is an equal and opposite reaction.
鲍勃·布利斯
"Bob Bliss."
你好
Hello?
请讲
Um, speaking.
好的
OK.
今天吗
Today?
好 我半个小时后就到
Um, yes, I can be there in about half an hour.
好的
Right.
好的 我知道你不能直说
Right, er, I know you... ..you can't tell me,
是不是关于我的检查报告
but is it regarding my test?
不 不 我明白
No, no. No, no, I understand.
明白 好的
I understand. Right.
好的 谢谢你
Yeah, OK, thank you.
妈妈 你猜怎么着
Hey, Mum, guess what?
鲍勃在周六的赛马大赛上下注了
You know Bob put a bet on the Grand National on Saturday?
他的马赢了
Well, his horse only won.
他以33比1的赔率投注了60英镑
He put 60 quid on at 33-1.
什么
Sorry?
鲍勃赢了将近2000英镑
Bob won nearly two grand,
他说他要给我一半的钱 作为我的大学学费
and he said he's going to give me half of it for my uni fund.
我不想让他再来这里了
I don't want him coming round here any more.
什么
What?
你不能拿这笔钱 你听到了吗
And you're not to take that money, do you hear?
为什么 他怎么了
Why? What's wrong with him?
我们不知道他的身份
We've got no idea who he is.
他可能是任何人
He could be anybody.
不过是偶然出现在
He's just... ..just some weirdo
我们家门口的一个怪人
who just turned up at our door one day.
你有什么毛病
What is wrong with yer?
为什么要破坏掉
Why do you have to ruin anything decent
我生活中发生的所有好事
that comes into my life?
-我这是为你好 -到底怎么回事
It's for your own good. -What happened?
你是不是可怜巴巴地朝他献殷勤来着
Did you pathetically come on to him?
-我没有时间搞这个 -你总是没有时间
-I haven't got time for this. -You've never got time.
每当我试图和你说话 你总是在忙别的事情
Whenever I try and talk to you, you're always doing something else.
做饭 打扫卫生 洗衣服
Cooking, cleaning, washing your clothes,
凑钱送你上大学
trying to scrape together enough money
to send you to university!
那就别费劲了
Well, don't bother!
我要去新加坡读大学 爸爸会付钱的
I'm going to uni in Singapore, and Dad's paying for it.
-哈哈哈 -你这是什么意思 他都答应了
-Ha-ha-ha! -What do you mean "ha"? He promised.
什么 他还答应带你过圣诞节呢
What? Like he promised to take you over for Christmas?
算了
Well, fine, then!
那你去找他吧 看看会发生什么
Go running off to him and see what happens!
至少他相信我 你真是个该死的混蛋
Well, at least he believes in me. You're such a fuckin' bitch!
懂吗
Do you know...?
对不起 扎克
Sorry, Zach.
我很抱歉 扎克
I'm sorry, Zach.
扎克
Zach...
Zach?
听着 我得去
Listen, I've got to go to the...
她不在家
She's not here.
我有一些现金给你
I've got some cash for you.
来自国家障碍赛马大赛 双写G
From the gee-gees - double G.
我不能收
I'm not allowed to take it.
为什么不能收
Why not?
你又和你妈妈吵架了吗
Have you had another row with your mum?
或许我不该多管闲事
Maybe I shouldn't have interfered.
拿去
Here.
我给她买了一些花
I got her these.
黄玫瑰 双写L
Yellow roses - double L.
这是她最喜欢的花
Those are her favourites.
你一直在偷窥我们吗
Have you been stalking us?
倒点水 把它们插起来吧
Do you want to put them in some water?
好吧
OK.
你对多普勒效应有所了解吗
Have you learned anything yet about the Doppler effect?
双写P 双写F
Double P, double F.
它描绘了波的频率变化
It describes the changing frequency of a wave in relation
与相对于该波源运动的观察者有关
to an observer moving relative to the source of that wave for example,
例如为什么警车在接近时 警笛的音调较高
why a police siren is higher in pitch when it approaches -
双写P 而它开走时音调较低
double P - and lower in pitch when it drives away.
这就像时间一样
It's like time.
在你年轻的时候 时间是缓慢的
It drags when you're young,
到了你年老的时候 它飞快地流逝
but when you're older...it flies by.
你会发现自己在回首往事时
And you find yourself thinking about the things
希望有所改变 双写F
you wish you'd done differently - double F.
如果能回到40年前 你还是个孩子的时候
What you'd say to yourself if you could go back 40 years
你会对自己说些什么
to when you were a boy.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
在未来
In the future,
人们能够操纵引力波
it will be possible to manipulate gravitational waves,
正如我所说的 正如你所说的
as I said - as you said -
驾驭黑洞的力量
and harness the power of black holes.
-"驾驭”是双写S -这不重要 听着
-Harness is double S. -It doesn't matter. Listen.
我们认为仅仅存在于理论中的东西
What we thought was theoretical
实际上是可以实现的
can actually be achieved, if...
只要你能把握其中的物理规律 而你做到了
..you get the physics right, and you did.
做到了什么
Did what?
62不是我出生的年份
'62 isn't when I was born,
指的是我来自的那一年
it's where I came from.
对你妈妈好一点 扎克
Be kinder to your mother, Zach.
你永远只有一个母亲
You'll only ever have one -
科学永远改变不了这一点
science'll never change that.
她是你的
And yours...
是我们的
..ours...
她不会陪伴你很久了
..she's not going to be around for much longer.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
你在说什么呢
What are you talking about?
她就要死了 扎克
She's dying, Zach.
等到你去新加坡的时候
By the time you go away to Singapore,
你已经不再和她说话了
you'll have stopped speaking to each other,
然后一切就太晚了
and then it's going to be too late.
相信我
And believe me,
你的下半辈子一直在后悔
you'll spend the rest of your life regretting it.
你会把自己封闭起来
You'll close in on yourself.
连你自己的孩子都会离开你
Your own kids will walk away from you.
到那时你才会明白
And you'll understand too late
她为你牺牲了多少
just how much she sacrificed for you,
明白她是多么的勇敢
how incredibly brave she was,
这种内疚感会毁掉你的余生
and that guilt will cripple you for life.
不 你在胡说八道
No, this is bullshit!
听着 你一定要相信我 扎克 求求你了
You've got to believe me, Zach, please.
求求你了
Please.
我只需要你告诉她 我非常爱她
I just need you to tell her I love her. Very much.
这救不了她 但可以救你
It won't save her, but it could save you.
就当是随手行善了
Just a random act of kindness...
这样你可以重新开始我的生活
..so you can have my time again.
你好
Hello?
扎克 你能听到我吗
Zach, can you hear me?
你到底以为自己在做什么
What the fuck do you think you're doing?
扎克是我儿子 请问你是谁
Zach's my son. Who is this, please?
天哪 威尔逊太太 请你保持冷静
Oh, God. Er, please, Mrs Wilson, try to stay calm.
我认为你的儿子面临极大的危险
I think your son could be in grave danger.
这个电话的主人 千万不要相信他
The man whose phone this is, he...he's not to be trusted.
-明白吗 -你是说鲍勃吗
-Do you understand? -Do you mean Bob?
你不能让你儿子和他单独在一起
You mustn't leave your son alone with him.
可是他
But he's...
扎克
Zach?
威尔逊太太
Mrs Wilson...
-扎卡里 -让我跟他说话 拜托
-Zachary! -..let me speak to him...
你还好吗
Are you all right?
哦 没事了 没事了
Oh! Oh, it's OK, it's all right. It's OK.
我爱你 妈妈
I love you, Mum.
我也爱你
I love you, too!
我非常爱你
I love you so much.
一切都会好起来的
Everything's going to be OK.
我保证
I promise.
一切都会好起来的
Everything's going to be OK.
谢谢你们
Thank you.
谢谢你们过来
Thank you for coming.
谢谢你们
Thank you.
威尔逊博士 你女儿让我进来的
Dr Wilson? Your daughter let me in.
叫我扎克吧 大家都这么叫
Call me Zach, please. Everybody does.
-这是一场温馨的追悼会 -谢谢你
-It was a lovely service. -Thank you.
我母亲大概会觉得持续时间有点长
I'm sure me mother would've said it went on a bit too long,
不过很多人也这么说她
but then a lot of people said that about her, as well.
-她多大年龄去世的 -93岁
-How old was she? -93.
已经算是高寿了 即使以今天的标准来看
Ah, well, that's a very decent age, even by today's standards.
她像只坚强的老鸟
She was a tough old bird.
回到这里却看不见她 感觉很别扭
Strange being back in here without her.
对不起 我可以请你喝一杯吗
Sorry, can I, er, offer you a drink?
请给我一杯咖啡就好
I'll have a coffee, please, yes.
我的女儿们告诉我 你开了一个优酷频道
So, me daughters were telling me you have a Youku channel?
是的 我为孩子们拍一些科学小视频
Yes. I do little science videos for children,
都是很基础的东西
pretty basic stuff.
你还想采访我母亲
And you wanted to interview my mother?
没错 我想听她亲口讲述
That's right. I wanted to hear in her own words
她能回忆起的事情
what she could remember.
她是29年
She was one of the first people
第一批试用你的抗癌血清的人
to try your anti-cancer serum back in '29.
那是很久以前的事了
It was a long time ago.
时间是相对的
Well...Time is relative, so...
-要糖吗 -要 谢谢
-Sugar? -Yes, please.
所以你是一个真正的科学家
So, you're an actual scientist, then?
不是一个穿白大褂的演员
You're not an actor in a white coat?
对 我都有涉猎
Ha, yes, I do dabble.
实际上我本应该是
In fact, this could've been me,
世界著名的诺贝尔奖得主
world-famous Nobel Prize-winner,
但你骗了我 不是吗 扎克
but you cheated me out of that, didn't you, Zach?
在另一个时空中 你和我 我们是合作伙伴
In another time, we were partners, you and I.
我们一起研究出威尔逊布兰虫洞
We developed the Wilson-Brann wormhole together.
这是一个开天辟地的成果
It was a game-changer.
让我们赚了几十亿
It made us billions.
它消失了 它消失了
It's gone. It's gone, it's gone, it's gone!
但是因为在这条时间线中
But because, in this timeline,
你没有去新加坡学习物理
you never left to study physics in Singapore,
没有来剑桥大学研究黑洞
you never came to Cambridge to research black holes,
所以我们从来没有见过面
and so we...never met.
你一心一意钻研化学
You devoted your life to chemistry,
致力于肿瘤学研究
oncological research.
我最后以科学怪人布兰博士的身份
I ended up doing Youku videos
在优酷拍摄视频
as Dr Brann the Science Man.
你最好马上离开这里
I'd like you to leave now, please.
然后有一天 我在清理我的垃圾邮件时
And then, one day, I was clearing out my spam folder
发现了一条视频信息
and I found a video message
那是我给自己发的邮件
I had apparently just emailed to myself.
我察觉到 无需再过很长时间
I must've realised that I didn't have long
我那个版本的生活就将不复存在
before that version of my life ceased to exist.
你可以回到过去
You can go back in time...
我一直觉得自己过上了错误的人生
I always felt I was living the wrong life.
你把我本该有的人生偷走了
The life you stole from me...
我想把它要回来
..I want it back.
-它在哪里 -什么
-Where is it? -What?
跨时空发报机
The Trans-Temporal-Telegraph.
我们的时间机器
Our time machine.
你用它来探访小时候的自己
The one you used to visit yourself as a boy.
它就是一台破烂 我把它扔了
That was just junk. I got rid of it.
-我不相信你 -没骗你
-I don't believe you. -It's true.
鲍勃疯了
Bob was insane.
不
No.
我们要回去了 威尔逊博士
We're going back, Dr Wilson.
现在一切重启
It's time to reset.
不 求你了
No, please.
-求你了 我妈妈 -我不管
-Please. My mother... -Fuck her.
我不想受到你的间接伤害了
I'm not prepared to be your collateral damage.
真可恶
Oh, bloody hell...